I am applying for an Elementary Teacher position for the 2016-2017 school year. I would be a great addition to your team because as a teacher I am flexible, determined, and a great team player. I graduated from Kutztown University with a Bachelor's in Elementary Education certified to teach Pre-K to 4th grade. I am the best candidate to join your teaching team because I have been working as a First Grade Teacher in an urban school.

In my most recent position as a First grade teacher, I have learned a lot about teaching in a poverty setting. The school is about 20 minutes outside of D.C. About 50% of my student's parents only speak Spanish so during conferences or afternoon dismissal I have to get translators or use the Language Line to help me with communication. Teaching a school with students who are bilingual has its challenges but I overcome them by scaffolding with the use of visuals and audio to support the lessons. I teach all day in rotational centers. I find this best fits the needs and assistance of my students. A lot of families are illiterate so it's not uncommon that I have no home support with my students to get them to the required 2nd grade level. By the use of the rotational centers, it helps me support the needs of each individual student.

During my experiences I have found that I am great at adaptation, flexibility and learning. I have learned how to teach students in different ways to unlock their potential. I am flexibly by working with grade partners to follow school and state standards while keeping my teaching style my own. I welcome the opportunity to discuss any further information. Thank you for your time.

Sincerely,

Ryan Rettstadt

Ryan Rettstadt

Rrett484@live.kutztown.edu

2916 Cold Spring Way #371 Crofton, MD 21114 (215) 933-8122

Qualifications

Enthusiastic Flexible Dedicated

Hard Working Strong Technology Skills

Education

Kutztown University of Pennsylvania Kutztown, PA
Bachelors in Education May, 2014

Certified in Elementary Education PreK-4

GPA: 3.56

Honors

Dean's List Spring Semester 2013
Dean's List Spring Semester 2014

Teaching Experience

Hyattsville Elementary School

Hyattsville, MD

August 2014 - Present

First Grade Teacher

• At an urban school that is right outside of D.C.

- Responsible to plan, prepare, and deliver lessons in math, reading, science, health, social studies, and writing.
- Keep in contact with parents through a monthly newsletter, email, daily conversations, and homework calendar.
- Create and assign student assessments, assignments, and homework.
- Taught small group reading and mathematics centers by evaluating and observing the students' performance.
- Responsible by having the students reading at a minimum of a 16 DRA by the end of First grade.
- Managing student behavior in the classroom by creating and enforcing rules and procedures.

West Rockhill Elementary School

Sellersville, PA

Teacher Candidate, Clinical Experience

March 2013-May 2013

- Taught 1st Grade
- Responsible to teach Math, Science, Social Studies, Language Arts, Writing Workshop and Centers.
- Participated in Parent-Teacher Conferences and In-Service days.

Spring City Elementary School

Spring City, PA

Teacher Candidate, Clinical Experience

January 2013-March 2013

- Taught 2nd grade
- Responsible to teach Language Arts, Writing Workshop, Math, Science and Social Studies.

Washington Elementary School

Boyertown, PA

Pre-Student Teaching

October 2013-December 2013

- Co-Taught 4th grade
- Observed Cooperating Teacher, assessed students.
- Taught Math, Science, Language Arts, Social Studies and Spelling.
- Worked one-on-one, small group and whole group.

Work Experience

Life Path. Harleysville, PA
Social Care Worker April 2007-Present

Responsible to take care of mentally and physically handicapped. Held
accountable to prepare food, drive clients to and from work, and assist them in
learning programs.

References

Available upon request.